gnacio Reyes Valenzuela

□ (+56) 9-8912-5492 | ■ Ignacio.Reyes.ASTRO@gmail.com | ■ ignacio-reyes-valenzuela-9440a5269/

Summary_

Bachelor of Science, Astronomy mention. With knowledge in Astronomy, Physics, Cosmology, Photonics and Machine Learning. Has worked on a multidisciplinary team in a Astronomy Instrumentation research project. Open to work with team in and outside of Chile. With a respectable knowledge in English. Has the capacity to work on research projects in astronomy. Wants to broaden the professional experience.

Education

Pontificia Universida Católica de Chile

Macul, Chile

FACULTAD DE INGENIERÍA

2021-2022

- Diploma, in Python and Data Science
- · (Graduated with distinction)
- · E-learning modality

Universidad de Chile Santiago, Chile

FACULTAD DE CIENCIAS FÍSICAS Y MATEMÁTICAS

2013-2019

- · Bachelor of Sciences, Astronomy Mention
- (Graduated with Distinction)

Work Experience

Freelancer Weh

FIVERR. UPWORK, FREELANCER January, 2024 - Actual

- Provided a range of freelance services on multiple online platforms
- · Manged portafolio and interacted with clients.

Census Taker La Florida, Chile

INSTITUTO NACIONAL DE ESTADISTICAS

March 2024 - July 2024

- · Conducted door-to-door interviews and collected demographic data from households to ensure accurate population counts.
- **Research Assistant**

• Explained the purpose and importance of the census to respondents, addressing any questions or concerns.

LABORATORY OF ASTROPHOTONICS AND TERAHERTZ, UNIVERSIDAD DE CHILE

Santiago, Chile 2018 - 2020

- Assisted in the development and maintenance of the laboratory's thermal control systems, ensuring optimal operating conditions for sensitive experiments
- · Contributed to the implementation of the third receiver system of an heterodyne interferometer.

Las Condes, Chile **Research Asistant**

DEPARTAMENT OF ASTRONOMY, UNIVERSIDAD DE CHILE

Fall 2019

- Conducted an in-depth analysis of the spectral index in V883 Ori, contributing to the understanding of this celestial object's properties.
- Categorized the viscuos infalling of protoplanetary disk

Research assistant Las Condes, Chile

DEPARTAMENT OF ASTRONOMY, UNIVERSIDAD DE CHILE

January 2017

- Power Calibration of MINI Radio Telescope
- GMC345.5+1.0 molecular cloud observations during the month of January
- Analysed the differences between reference and observed data.

Publications

Application limit of the photocentre displacement to fundamental stellar parameters of fast rotators - Illustration on the edge-on fast rotator Regulus

MONTHLY NOTICES OF THE ROYAL ASTRONOMICAL SOCIETY.

2022

https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stac092

ACHILLES: AstronomiCal Heterodyne in Infrared-opticaL with muLtiapErtureS

SF2A-2019: PROCEEDINGS OF THE ANNUAL MEETING OF THE FRENCH SOCIETY OF ASTRONOMY AND ASTROPHYSICS.

2019

- Model review, circuit review, thermal systems calibration
- https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019sf2a.conf...39H/abstract



English PET B1 level, Michigan B2, working on IELTS Academic

Spanish Native level

Driver's Licence Chilean Class B licence

Programming languages Python
Data management system MySQL
Document Preparation System LaTeX

Lens simulation OSLO

Operating systems Windows, Mac, UNIX

3d Printing Makerbot Replicator 2

Office suites GoogleDocs, Microsoft Office, Power BI

Data Science Python Machine Learning Algorithms

Personal Interest

My interest comprise of:

- Developing my skills in the area of data analysis to improve my research capabilities.
- Reading science fiction and fantasy literature, which fuels my creativity and sense of wonder, provides my with inspiration for innovative thinking in scientific contexts and growing as a person.
- Keeping up to date with the latest discoveries and events in astronomy.

References_

Ph.D. Leonardo Bronfman

PROFESSOR

Department of Astronomy, Universidad de Chile leo@das.uchile.cl

Ph.D. René Méndez

PROFESSOR

Department of Astronomy, Universidad de Chile rmendez@uchile.cl

M.Sc. Miguel Piña

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER, Atacama Pathfinder Experiment miguel.pina@raig.uchile.cl